Rushiraj Brahmbhatt

Front End Developer

Ahmedabad, India | rbrahm812@gmail.com | +91 93274 29391

Objective

Around 4+ years of experience in the computer software industry with a demonstrated history of working as web/frontend developer to analysis, design, development, and deployment, of various applications with a primary focus on technologies like HTML5, CSS3, CSS pre-processors like LESS and SASS, JavaScript, JS libraries like ReactJS and Redux. I am enthusiastic about learning new technologies to evolve and be a better self.

Education

New York Institute of Technology, New York, USA

Jan 2016 - May 2017

Master's in Computer Science (GPA: 3.9)

Ganpat University, Gujarat, India

July 2011 - June 2015

Bachelor's in Computer Engineering (CGPA: 6.99)

Experience

Intern | CMC Limited, India

January 2015 - May 2015

- Using spring, Hibernate, HQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, and MVC developed government projects.
- Developed the E-tendering website for the online tendering process which helps' for the whole process of tendering in an organized manner.
- Worked on the Front End for the layout using the Web Design and for Backend using the Database Service & MVC.

Graduate Assistant | New York Institute of Technology

August 2016 - December 2016

- Gave technical help to faculty and student. Perform testing and analyse test results. Making Excel sheets for grades obtained by students. Preparing coding examples for students.
- Done Data Analysis and plotted graphs from large data of a taxi company using Python and Pandas.

Sr. Software Developer | Teamwork Solutions

Feb 2019 - Nov-2019

- Added new features to the existing web application with the help of HTML, ReactJS, CSS, AJAX, JQuery, Photoshop, Bootstrap and JavaScript and have provided data management to users.
- Using the UI Interface and the web application elements designed the websites.
- Fetch RESTful API using axios/fetch and manipulate fetched data using JSX(Javascript XML)

React Developer | UpForce Tech

Nov-2019 - Present

- Developing a single page application using React JS for web application to give a better user experience.
- Working with customized API and made them available to components using reducers and actions from Redux.
- Used React-Router to turn applications into SPA.
- Built reusable class components using React Redux based on the visual designs.
- Used HTTP Client Module for consuming back-end APIs and used async/await and Promises to deal with asynchronous data.
- Designed dynamic and multi-browser compatible Web pages using HTML5 and CSS3.
- Developed desktop applications using Electron and React
- Also integrated firebase to manage database using cloud firestore

Personal Projects

Daily Todo App | React/Redux + Firebase

Project Development Duration: 1 month

- Developed daily Todo application using React for front end development, used Redux for state management, Firebase(cloud firestore) for database management and Material-UI for designing and styling of the components and app
- User can add, update, delete Todos as per their requirement
- Implemented calendar date-picker to select the date and fetch Todos of that particular date
- Also user can set the notification timing to get desktop notification for adding the morning
 Todos and evening Todos and also they can copy all the Todos to their clipboard

Github link: https://github.com/rushi812/daily-todo **Live Demo:** https://daily-todo-app-75539.web.app/

Technical Skills

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, LESS, SASS, Bootstrap, React Bootstrap, Material UI, JavaScript, AJAX,

JSON, Typescript

JavaScript Libraries: ReactJS, Redux, NextJS

Content Management: WordPress.

Project Management: Github, Bit bucket, Jira **Collaboration Apps:** Slack, Microsoft Teams

IDE's and Development Tools: Notepad++, Sublime text, ATOM, Web Storm, Visual Studio Code

Debugging Tools: Firebug, Chrome Developer, IE Developer Tools, React Developer Tool, Redux

Developer tools

Database: Firebase

Operating System: Windows XP/Vista/7/8/10, MAC OS X, Linux